Let's take a look at what an average 16-year-old has endured in their lifetime.
At birth, an Israeli land, air, and sea blockade has affected every aspect of his or her life,
from food to health and education.
At the age of two, the child would have lived through 23 days of devastating air and ground
attacks.
Nearly 1,400 Palestinians were killed during Israel's Operation Cast Lead, 320 were children.
Then in 2012, when the child would be five years old, they would have survived an eight-day
assault that killed more than 80 people, most of them women and children.
At age seven, the child would have endured a 50-day Israeli onslaught.
At least 2,310 Palestinians were killed in 2014, 551 were children.
As a young teenager, he or she would have witnessed the aftermath of Israeli attacks that lasted
111 days.
260 Palestinians were killed, 67 were children.
And now, another war on Gaza, this one far worse than any other.
At age 16 today, an average Palestinian child is living through what's been described as
genocide, 60 days of war in which more than 16,248 people have been killed, more than 7,112
of them, children.